bpcdn.net 2019-10-05

# Privacy Statement

## Responsible body for this Internet offer

Bigpoint GmbH

Drehbahn 47-48

20354 Hamburg

Tel.: +49 (0) 40 8814130 (no support)

[info@bigpoint.net](mailto:info@bigpoint.net) (no support)

## Name and address of the data protection officer

Data protection agency

Maximilian Hartung

Frauentorstraße 9

86152 Augsburg

Tel.: +49 821 90786458

datenschutz@bigpoint.com

### General

This privacy statement informs you of which personal data is being collected by Bigpoint as part of our Internet services and games. It also explains how that data is processed and used. The protection of your personal information is important to us.

Your data is protected against unauthorized access and loss through the use of various electronic, technical, physical, administrative and contractual measures. Bigpoint has taken the necessary technical and organizational precautions to ensure that the regulations for data privacy are respected both internally as well as by external service providers.

This privacy statement contains transparent and clear information to ensure that visitors to our site and customers are well informed regarding the collection, processing and use of their personal data.

## Personal data

Personal data is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (e.g. name, address, telephone number, date of birth or email address). Basically, you can use our online offer without providing personal information, however the use of certain services may require the provision of personal information, e.g. registration for our games products and services or participation in a competition.

## Legal basis and processing purposes

We collect personal data for the following purposes:

  * the provision of this online offer and the performance of a contract in accordance with [our Terms of Service/TS](https://legal.bigpoint.com/DE/terms-and-conditions/en-GB)

  * provided by you upon registration at one of our websites or for one of our games;

  * when these are provided by you during an inquiry;

  * when these are provided by you for the use and payment of fee-based goods and services;

  * our own and third-party advertising, market research and reach measurement to the extent permitted by law or based on consent.

  * to shape and improve our offer as required, partially in pseudonymized and/or anonymous form

  * to fulfill legal obligations, and, in particular, to meet the requirements for preserving data.

We also process user data to the extent that it is necessary for the performance of services or for the billing of these services. This refers in particular to game processes, game scores and information regarding the use and settlement of services. We also use your data to communicate with you. This includes, in particular, the provision of assistance and support as well as the provision of important contract information. Subject to your consent, we keep you informed about news, events and promotions either via e-mail, phone call or text message.

Provided that you have used the Portal or Games and Services for an extended period of time, we would like to inform you that we also use data from our predecessor company, and current subsidiary, Bigpoint S.à.r.l. Co, SCS, 10A rue Henri M. Schnadt, L-2530 Luxembourg. This refers to master data that we require to continue offering games without interruption. This data especially refers to game processes, game scores and information regarding the use and settlement of services.

## Legitimate interests in data processing

Based on the processing of data under Article 6 f DS-GVO (German General Data Protection Regulation) our legitimate interest is the conduct of our business, in particular with regard to the wellbeing of our employees and the company owners.

## Data protection in the application process

We collect personal data from applicants to process applications, which will be saved upon the conclusion of a contract of employment to implement the employment relationship. The legal regulations shall be considered here. In the event of a rejection, the application documentation will be deleted no later than after two months. An exception to this is, for example, if we have to retain the application documents as evidence in a process relating to the German General Equal Treatment Act, or if other legitimate interests exist. We will request your consent should we retain application documents in our pool of applicants for a longer period.

## Credit information

For German users, we will obtain information about your previous payment history from infoscore Consumer Data GmbH, Rheinstr. 99, 76532 Baden-Baden, insofar as this is necessary for the conclusion or performance of a contract between the relevant person and the responsible body.

## Cookies and the collection of log files

Within the context of the use of our websites, forums and games, Bigpoint collects the following non-personal information:

  * IP addresses including time and date

  * cookies, local flash data

  * statistical information such as the browser type, operating system, redirecting URL, date, time, pages used, total time of use, frequency of use

This data is used in statistical analyses for anonymous data records.

IP addresses and the corresponding Internet information are saved for a period of maximum of six months within the scope of our legal obligations regarding data storage. Furthermore, these are stored to secure data and ensure our system’s stability and reliability. In specific situations, Bigpoint may also use your IP address and the corresponding Internet information to track and stop use of multiple accounts for fraudulent purposes. In cases such as these, Bigpoint will seek the consent for such use within the framework of the relevant game conditions.

Cookies Authorization:

Despite the fact that this is stated in the Privacy Statement, we would like to expressly inform you that we employ the use of cookies to optimize the use of our Portal and Games and Services, especially regarding user experience. By accepting out Terms and Conditions, you authorize the use of cookies. At any point in the future, you can object to the use of cookies by sending an e-mail to the following address datenschutz@bigpoint.com. For all additional questions regarding cookies, please contact us via the same e-mail address.

**How can you prevent the use of cookies or delete cookies?**

You can disable the storage of cookies in your browser settings and delete the cookies stored saved in your browser at any time. However, please note that this online offer may not function, or only to a limited extent, without the use of cookies.

In addition, please note that contradictions against the creation of usage profiles work partially through opt-out cookies. Should you delete all the cookies, a contradiction may therefore no longer be taken into account and must be collected from you again.

## Range measurement

Our online service uses the “Scalable Central Measuring method” (SCM / SCMnG) from INFOline Ltd. GmbH (https://www.infonline.de) to determine statistical values for the use our offers. Anonymous measured data will be collected. For the recognition of computer systems, the SCM measurement method alternatively uses either a cookie with the ID “ioam.de”, “ivwbox.de”, a local storage object or a signature that is automatically created from different browser-transmitted information. IP addresses are only processed in anonymous form. The range measurement was developed under strict observation of data protection policies. The objective of the range measurement system is to statistically determine how intensely and by how many users a website is being used. At no point in time will individual users be identified. Their identities will always remain protected. They will receive no promotional materials via the system. For online offers that belong to the Association of the Distribution of Advertising Materials (Informationsgemeinschaft zur Feststellung der Verbreitung von Werbeträgern e.V., IVW – www.ivw.eu) or are a part of the German Study Group for Online Research (Arbeitsgemeinschaft Online-Forschung e.V., AGOF – www.agof.de) study, “Internet Facts,” the usage statistics will be published on a monthly basis by AGOF, the Working Group of Media Analysis (Arbeitsgemeinschaft Media-Analyse e.V., ag.ma - www.agma-mmc.de), as well as by the IVW. The results can be viewed at: http://www.agof.de, http://www.agma-mmc.de and http://www.ivw.eu. In addition to the publication of measured data, the IVW regularly checks the SCM process to make sure it stays consistent with the rules of data protection. Additional information about the SCM process can be found on the INFOnline GmbH website (https://www.infonline.de), which operates the system itself, on the AGOF’s data protection website (http://www.agof.de/datenschutz), as well as on the IVW’s data protection website (http://www.ivw.eu). You can object to SCM processing your data via the following website: http://optout.ioam.de and http://optout.ivwbox.de.

## Data transfer and service providers

We will treat your data with the strictest confidentiality and will not disclose it to any third parties, unless you have given us your express permission to do so. We may however be required by law to disclose your information in certain situations (such as to an investigating authority) where the transfer takes place only within the framework required by legal conventions. In individual cases, subsidiaries, parent companies or third parties may provide services on our behalf. This mainly concerns the handling of payment transactions by external service providers (PayPal, Global Collect, etc.) and, in the case of default, by a debt collection company. Moreover, we provide your data to affiliated companies of the Bigpoint Group for marketing purposes and to further develop and improve our games. These affiliated companies of the Bigpoint Group and external companies are obligated to handle your data confidentially and securely, and may only use your data insofar as it is required for completing their directive. Service providers are generally involved as processors who are only authorized to process the personal data of users of this online offer in accordance with our explicit instructions.

## Period of storage/retention periods

We store your data for as long as this is necessary for the provision of our online offer and the associated services or if we have a legitimate interest in the further storage of such. In all other cases, we will delete your personal information except for such information as we may need to maintain in accordance with contractual or statutory requirements (e.g. tax or commercial purposes, e.g. invoices). Contractual retention periods may also arise from contracts with third parties (e.g. owners of copyrights and ancillary copyrights). We will block any data that is subject to a retention period until the expiry of the relevant period.

## Game Information and Partner Offers

By checking the box next to “Game Information and Partner Offers”, you are granting us your express consent to receive this information. Your consent will be recorded and saved, and may be revoked at any time by using our contact form ([www.bigpoint.net/support/](https://www.bigpoint.net/support/)).

## Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, These services are provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. If, however, you activate the Anonymize IP option on this website, Google will remove the end of your IP address so it only locates you as within the member states of the European Union or other members of the European Economic Area. Only in rare cases will the complete IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and then shortened there. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage. The operator of this website will use information gathered via interest-related advertising as well as third-party visitor data (e.g. age, gender and interests) for the purpose of evaluation in order to find out more about the users of this website. No person-related data shall be used here; only a statistical evaluation of anonymous data sets shall be carried out. Google will not associate your IP address as transmitted by Google Analytics with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Furthermore, you can prohibit Google from collecting and analyzing the data generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plugin available here [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de). Should you wish to adapt or prevent the analysis of your demographic or interest-based information, you can disable Google Analytics display ads and adapt the ads in the Google Display Network: [https://www.google.com/settings/ads](https://www.google.com/settings/ads?hl=de).

If you access this website via a mobile device (smartphone, tablet, etc.) you may object to the use of your data by Google by clicking a separate link in the dialog box displayed.

## Online Behavioral Advertising

The advertising on our websites will be optimized according to your predicted interests by collecting and processing anonymous data about your usage of our websites. German telecommunications provider ProSiebenSat.1 Digital GmbH, in cooperation with online marketing company SevenOne Media GmbH, a subsidiary of the ProSiebenSat.1 Group and ProSiebenSat.1 Digital GmbH, in accordance with §§ 15 ff of the German Stock Corporation Act, is responsible for collecting the aforementioned data. To this end, third party companies place cookies on your computer to collect user data. The data collected is information when, for example, you navigate the pages of this online offer or click on ads. This allows us to analyze the use of online ads and to provide you with ads that could be of interest to you and correspond to your personal preferences (Online Behavioral Advertising). No personal information, such as name, address, e-mail address etc., will be collected. IP addresses are kept anonymous so that they cannot be allocated to any specific person.

If you want to opt out of receiving Online Behavioral Advertising, you can block the placement of cookies on your computer by changing your browser settings so that it does not accept cookies. Furthermore, you may prevent third-party companies, employees on our behalf, from using cookies via the following links:

Nugg.ad AG: [http://ad-choices.nuggad.net](http://ad-choices.nuggad.net/)

AudienceScience: <http://www.audiencescience.com/de/privacy>

Criteo GmbH: <http://www.criteo.com/privacy>

Additionally, we permit other third parties, e.g. media agencies, to use cookies to analyze the use of online advertising and to display advertising in our online offer that could be of interest to you by analyzing your personal preferences. Additionally, this should enable advertising customers to reach their target audience more accurately without large wastage. For this purpose, user statistics can, for example, be anonymously compiled and the data can be used for market research purposes, without tracing this information back to a specific person. Further information about this provider’s Data Privacy Policy and about objecting to the use of cookies for the purpose of usage-based online advertising can be found on SevenOne Media GmbH’s website at: <https://www.sevenonemedia.de/web/sevenone/datenerhebung-anderer-dienstleister1>. You can also control the placement of third-party cookies on your computer through a respective setting on your browser.

SevenOne Media GmbH has voluntarily agreed to comply with the self-regulatory principles of the German Privacy Policy Council for Online Advertising (DDOW - Deutschen Datenschutzrat Online-Werbung). The self-regulatory code valid for us (Code for Telemedia Providers - First Parties) can be found at: [www.meine-cookies.org/ddow.html](http://www.meine-cookies.org/ddow.html).

Facebook

Embedded on our website are various Facebook links. This web presence is operated exclusively by Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (Facebook).

Within the scope of our web presence, these links are identified by the Facebook logo or by the phrase ‘Like’ (no Facebook plugins are used).

Should a user click one of these links, then the Facebook plugins are activated and establish a direct connection via the user’s browser to a Facebook server.

Provided that the user clicks one of the aforementioned links while visiting our website, and is logged into their personal Facebook account, the information will be forwarded to Facebook that the user has visited our website. Facebook can associate your visit to the website to your account. Facebook can associate your visit to the website to your account.

This data is transferred to and saved by Facebook. To prevent this, the user must log out of their account before clicking the link. The functions embedded in the links by Facebook, especially the transfer of data and user information, are not activated by visiting our website, but rather by clicking the corresponding links.

The purpose and scope of data collection via Facebook, the processing and use of such data, as well as your rights thereof and personal settings regarding privacy protection can be found in the Facebook privacy settings section (http://de-de.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php).

For further questions pertaining to the collection, processing or use of individual user data and, regarding the disclosure, correction, blocking or deleting of data, please contact our data protection supervisors.

Facebook Connect

We’re offering you the opportunity to sign up for our services through Facebook Connect. In order to do this, you will be redirected to Facebook where you can log in using your Facebook user data. Your Facebook account will then be linked to our services. Depending on your Facebook settings, linking your account will allow the following data to be transmitted to us and/or retrieved by us: name, date of birth and email address.

We shall only use this information for identification purposes and contract processing. For more information on Facebook Connect and the privacy settings, please refer to the Data Privacy Policy and Terms of Use of Facebook Inc.

Google Plus

Our web presence also employs the Google Plus “+1” link, which is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States (Google). The link can be identified by the “+1” symbol against a white or color background.

If the user opens one of our websites containing such a link, the user’s browser establishes a direct connection to a Google server. The contents of the “+1” link are transferred directly to your browser, which then integrates said content in the webpage. We therefore have no control over the data whatsoever that Google collects via the link, but would expect user IP addresses to be collected.

The purpose and scope of data collection via Google, the processing and use of such data, as well as your rights thereof and personal settings regarding privacy protection can be found in the Google privacy settings section http://www.google.com/intl/de/+/policy/+1button.html

If a user is a Google Plus member and does not wish to have their data collected and linked to their saved Google member data via our web presence, the user must log out of their Google Plus account before visiting our websites.

## Mobile apps

Our apps are provided through various app and software platforms, including the Apple App Store, the Google Play Store and social networks like Facebook. If you access, register on or use the platform or social network, personal data may be collected and used by the respective platform or social network over which we basically have no influence. You will find all the relevant information in the privacy policy or privacy statement of each platform or social network.

## IT security

With the help of an IT security provider, we collect and process specific data anonymously about the features of the terminal device used by the user (“device-specific data”), raw data from the TCP/IP connection and data on the use of our website by using so-called cookies and tracking technology to prevent the abuse of our services.

Initially, the IP address is also collected and processed but encrypted within a few seconds. No personal data is collected or stored. The information is stored with the IT security provider in a database for the prevention of fraud.

If, on our website, you conclude a contract for pecuniary interest or if the conclusion of a contract for pecuniary interest is approaching (e.g. at the beginning of the checkout process), we retrieve a risk evaluation about the terminal device you are using from the IT security provider’s database which has been stored there.

The risk evaluation is used – but not exclusively – as a basis for deciding whether a contract for pecuniary interest can be concluded.

Should it come to our attention that a user is or has attempted to abuse our services, we shall also transmit collected data to the IT security provider. In this process, however, only device-specific data, and no personal data, shall be transmitted.

## Right of revocation, deletion of data

If you have given us consent to process personal data, you can withdraw this consent at any time.

Bigpoint deletes your personal data insofar as it is no longer needed or required, or if you have requested the deletion of this data. Please note that data cannot be deleted if there are legal or other requirements to store the data, or if we need it to bill our services.

## Information on data protection, viewing information and the correction, deletion and blocking of data

For general questions regarding this privacy statement and data protection, or if you would like to query, correct, block or delete your private data in accordance with the legal stipulations, please contact us via email or post, stating your user ID, username, email address and, if applicable, your game. HYPERLINK “http://de.bigpoint.com/support/” You can contact us or the data protection officer directly via the contact details at the top of this Privacy Statement.

## Right of appeal with the regulatory body

You have the right to file a complaint with a data protection authority. You can contact the data protection authority which covers your place or residence or region or the authority which is responsible for us, which is: the Hamburg Commission for Data Protection and Freedom of Information, Klosterwall 6 (Block C), 20095 Hamburg, Tel.: 040 / 428 54 – 4040, Fax: 040 / 428 54 – 4000, email: [mailbox@datenschutz.hamburg.de](mailto:mailbox@datenschutz.hamburg.de)

## Security provisions and technical information

All the employees in our company receive regular training in data protection, and are committed to data protection. Our computer center and our in-house EDP department are constantly adapting the technical security precautions to the current security conditions and requirements. Both are subject to constant monitoring by our internal procedures and the data protection officer. Nevertheless, Internet technologies may have security loopholes that cannot guarantee full protection. Users can therefore submit data to us via other methods, i.e. phone or fax.

**The following technical info will enable you to adjust the privacy settings in your browser.**

**Internet Explorer:**

For info visit:

http://windows.microsoft.com/de-de/internet-explorer/delete-manage-cookies#ie=ie-11-win-7

**Mozilla Firefox:**

For info visit:

https://support.mozilla.org/de/kb/cookies-erlauben-und-ablehnen

**Google Chrome:**

For info visit:

https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647

**Safari:**

For info visit:

http://help.apple.com/

Version date: 11.12.2017
